

Website plamen-k.github.io

Email p.kolev22@gmail.com

Github https://github.com/plamen-k

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/plamen-kolev-465915a7

ABOUT

My name is Plamen Kolev and I am a Newcastle, England based developer specializing in web application development, system automation and web app deployment. I enjoy playing with emerging technologies and stay up to date with thech trends.

In the past years, I have gained knowledge in Perl, Bash, Unix-based operating systems, python for web development and PHP.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Intern, Intel Corporation

August 2015 - September 2016

Worked on high-perormance, security projects.

Created automated tests using bash, Perl and inhouse tools. Developed scripts to automate product integration and deployment in a large, multi-national team

Interviewer, Populus Data Solutions

April 2014 - June 2015

Conducted national studies across Britain on sociopolitical issues

Lead Graphic Designer, Ivesto Company
September 2012 - June 2013

Worked full time as a website manager and designer where I had the opportunity to improve the user experience and maintain the two websites of the company.

PROJECTS

Neven Body care

5 August - 28 August 2016

Created a website for the neven brand

Secure Coding Presentation

5 May 2016

Lloyds Banking

September 2014 - March 2015

Developed and designed a website with restful API that hooks to an Android application for the british bank Lloyds. The product was produced as part of a team.

HackNE Hackathon

31 October 2014

Co-organized a hackathon in the North East, United Kingdom backed by Major League Hacking EU.

Created the website for the event, PR and print design materials.

PAConsulting

12 February 2014

Developed an environmental friendly hardware & software solution with the Raspberry Pi that involves predictive light automation and controll.

EDUCATION

BSc. Computer Science, Newcastle University September 2013 - Present

Object-oriented programing, design & development of software. Web design & construction: delivery and consumption of web content, database technologies. Computer Architecture: Parallel Computer

Architectures

Low-level programing. Software Engineering principles and lifecycle, scalability and maintnance. Team projects, working as part of a group.